{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The class of immunoglobulins which can cross the placenta is", "opta": "IgM", "optb": "IgG", "optc": "IgA", "optd": "IgD", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Self reactive antibodies are not found in significant concentration in normal serum because", "opta": "it is impossible to generate a self-reactive antibody", "optb": "self reactive B cells are killed by CD8 T cells", "optc": "B cells that are stimulated via their surface bound antibody in the absence of T cell help to commit suicide", "optd": "self reactive B cells switch to IgA which is all secreted and not present in serum", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Simulation of which of the following will lead to appearance of first antibody to appear following stimulation by an antigen?", "opta": "IgM", "optb": "IgA", "optc": "IgE", "optd": "IgG", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Antigen binding sites of an immunoglobulin are located in", "opta": "light chain alone", "optb": "heavy chain alone", "optc": "Fc region of the antibody", "optd": "Fab regions of the antibody", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following mediates Type I hypersensitivity reaction?", "opta": "IgE", "optb": "IgG", "optc": "IgM", "optd": "IgD", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following theory of antibody production is most widely accepted?", "opta": "Side chain theory", "optb": "Clonal selection theory", "optc": "Direct template theory", "optd": "Indirect template theory", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is the most efficient complement fixing class of antibody?", "opta": "IgE", "optb": "IgA", "optc": "IgM", "optd": "IgG", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The class of immunoglobulin, most abundant in body is", "opta": "IgD", "optb": "IgE", "optc": "IgG", "optd": "IgM", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not a function of IgG?", "opta": "Major antibody in serum", "optb": "First antibody type produced against an antigen during the primary antibody response", "optc": "Activates or fixes complement", "optd": "Involved in opsonization", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "J chain is present in", "opta": "IgA", "optb": "IgM", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "IgE", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Heat-labile class of immunoglobulins include", "opta": "IgA", "optb": "IgE", "optc": "IgG", "optd": "IgM", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following (s) is/are function (s) of Fc fragment of IgG?", "opta": "It determines catabolic rate", "optb": "It binds complement", "optc": "It is related to passage of IgG across the placental barrier", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the phylogenetically oldest immunoglobulin?", "opta": "IgE", "optb": "IgM", "optc": "IgG", "optd": "All are similar", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The secretary component of sIgA is", "opta": "made by plasma cells that secrete dimeric IgA", "optb": "added to dimeric IgA by the M cell", "optc": "formed by cleavage of an epithelial cell receptor used to transport the dimeric IgA across the epithelial cell", "optd": "made by T cells", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Anti-Rh antibodies are", "opta": "IgG type", "optb": "IgA type", "optc": "IgE type", "optd": "IgD type", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not a function of IgA?", "opta": "Protect mucosal surfaces", "optb": "Fix complement", "optc": "Protect eyes", "optd": "Agglutinate antigen", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}